假设我们正在运行一个承诺驱动器
let's say we're running a pledge drive
在我们的避难所建造鳄鱼沼泽
to build a crocodile swamp on our refuge
哎呀，我希望我们不会吸引锁定怪物
gee I hope we don't attract a lock ness monster
人们会承诺很多
people would pledge a lot to see that
无论如何，我们的服务器将如何处理承诺
in any event how's our server going to handle pledges
很好地创造一个承诺
well to create a pledge
姓名和金额将发送到我们的服务器
a name and an amount will be sent to our server
作为发布请求
as a post request
我们将该请求路由到创建
we'll route that request to the create
质押控制人的行动
action of a pledge controller
这将反过来
which will in turn
将质押信息发送到外部服务
send the pledge information to an external service
通过它的 api 因为
via its api because
毕竟我们正忙着经营一个野生动物保护区
after all we're busy running a wildlife refuge
也懒得处理所有
and can't be bothered to handle all
承诺驱动的复杂性
the intricacies of a pledge drive
你知道像管理用户帐户
you know like managing user accounts
向信用卡等收费
charging credit cards and the like
所以我们会让外部服务处理所有这些
so we'll let the external service handle all of those
细节然后我们什么时候想要得到所有的承诺
details then when we want to get all the pledges
我们将向我们的服务器发送一个获取请求
we'll send a get request to our server
我们将路由该请求
we'll route that request
质押控制器的索引动作
to the index action of the pledge controller
这将转身
which will turn around
并从外部服务获取承诺
and fetch the pledges from the external service
但
but
假设我们只对显示这三个感兴趣
suppose we're only interested in displaying the three
最近的承诺
most recent pledges
不是所有的承诺
not all the pledges
好，而不是打外部服务
well rather than hitting the external service
每次我们想显示最近的承诺
every time we want to display recent pledges
我们将创建一个内存现金
we'll create an in memory cash
何时创建承诺
when pledges are created
将它们全部发送到外部服务
will send them all to the external service
但只保留最近的三个现金
but only keep a cash of the three most recent ones
所以当一个新的承诺出现时
so when a new pledge comes in
我们将取消最古老的承诺
we'll bump the oldest pledge out of
现金并添加最新的现金并这样做
the cash and add the newest one in and in doing so
只保留最近的三个
only keep the most recent three
然后当要求最近的承诺时
then when the recent pledges are requested
我们将直接从现金中退回
we'll return them straight from the cash
现在我们已经知道如何处理 git 和 post 请求了
now we already know how to handle git and post request
我们在之前的模块中已经做到了
we've done that in previous modules
所以我们已经准备好代码让我们领先一步
so we've prepared that code to give us a head start
在处理程序 ex 中，我们定义了两条新路线
in handler ex we've defined two new routes
所以如果我们收到一个关于承诺的帖子请求
so if we get a post request for pledges
我们要委托
we're going to delegate
到质押控制器的 crate 操作
to the crate action of a pledge controller
如果我们收到一个获取 slash 承诺的请求
and if we get a get request for slash pledges
我们将委托给那个 index 动作
we're going to delegate to the index action of that
同质押控制器
same pledge controller
我们继续创建了质押控制器
and we went ahead and created the pledge controller
你在这里看到它的承诺控制器前
you see it over here pledge controller ex
它有一个 crate 动作和一个 index 动作
it has a crate action and an index action
crate 动作只是捕获
the crate action just captures the
名称和挂载参数
name and the mount parameters
然后它需要发送该质押信息
and then it needs to send that pledge information
到外部服务并兑现
to the external service and also cash it
所以我们将在一个名为
so we'll do that in a function called
创建承诺通知
create pledge notice
它需要两个参数名称的数量
it takes two arguments the name in the amount
然后在响应正文中我们只是说
and then in the response body we just say
无论金额是多少，都承诺的名字
name pledged whatever the amount is
然后在索引动作中我们需要得到原因
then in the index action we need to get the reason
现金认捐
pledges from the cash
我们将在一个函数中做到这一点
we're going to do that in a function
称为最近的承诺
called recent pledges
回报那些承诺
the returns those pledges
然后我们只是检查它们
and then we just inspect them
并将它们放入响应正文中
and put them in the response body
所以我们需要定义两个
so we need to define two
函数创建质押函数和
functions this create pledge function and
近期认捐功能
recent pledges function
在这个中定义那些是没有意义的
and it doesn't make sense to define those in this
控制器模块
controller module
所以我们将在一个名为的新模块中定义这些函数
so we'll define those functions in a new module called
质押服务器
pledge server
然后我们将调用该模块上的函数
and then we'll call the functions on that module
所以这将是
so this is going to be
服务质押服务器
serve pledge server
就拿那个
and just take that
我们将呼吁最近的承诺
and we're going to call recent pledges on that
相同的模块
same module
现在让我们继续创建质押服务器模块
now let's go ahead and create the pledge server module
它将在 lib 调查目录中
it's going to be in the lib survey directory
插入服务器 dx
plug server dx
服务点承诺服务器
servey dot pledge server
然后是第一个
and then that first
我们想要的函数叫做 crate 质押
function that we want is called crate pledge
它需要一个名字和一个数量
it takes a name and an amount
然后这个函数应该做什么
and then what should this function do
先好了
well first
它需要将质押发送到外部服务
it needs to send the pledge to the external service
所以假设我们有一个函数叫做
so let's say we have a function called
发送服务承诺
send pledge to service
我们就直接把名字和金额穿梭
we'll just go ahead and shuttle the name and the amount
到那个功能
over to that function
然后它会返回一个元组
and then it's going to return a tuple
如果它成功了
if it's successful it's going to be
亚当还好，然后是一些身份证
the adam okay and then some id
它可能就像一个交易ID
it might be like a transaction id
质押或质押 ID
of the pledge or the pledge id
只是
just
该承诺创建的一些唯一标识符
some unique identifier that that pledge got created
我们假设我们的承诺总是成功创建
we'll assume our pledge is always successfully created
但你可以想象返回一个不同的元组
but you can imagine returning a different tuple
如果有空气
and if there's an air
那么你可以使用
then you can use
处理成功的案例语句
a case statement to handle either the success
或失败
or the failure
好吧，现在这个罪恶承诺服务功能
okay now for this sin pledge to service function
我要去
I'm going to
为那个罪做一个私人的功能承诺服务
make a private function for that sin pledge to service
我们只是要解决这个问题
and we're just going to stub this out
不是
we're not
实际上是将其发送到外部服务
actually going to send it to an external service
所以我不会使用这个名字
so I'm not going to use the name
所以我将使用下划线名称
so I'm going to use underscore name
这样我们就不会收到任何编译器警告和
just so we don't get any compiler warnings and
下划线安装
underscore mount
在这口井的主体中，我们会有一些代码
and in the body of this well we would have some code
代码在这里发送承诺
code goes here to send pledge
对外服务
to external service
然后我们将返回一个
and then we'll just return a
罐头响应，所以它将是一个元组
canned response so it's going to be a tuple
我们假设它
we're going to assume it
总是返回 ok 作为第一个元素
always returns ok as the first element
然后我们需要一个 id
and then we need an id
只是为了让它变得有趣
and just to make it interesting
我将使用一个字符串
I'm going to use a string
它将被承诺冲刺
it's going to be pledged dash
然后我们将生成我们的随机数
and then we're going to generate our random number
只是为了让我们在这里有一些独特的东西
just so that we have something unique here
我将使用 rand 模块
and I'm going to use the rand module
这是一个城市模块
that's an urban module
它具有统一的功能
and it has a function uniform
它会通过它 1000 并且会返回
and it will pass it 1000 and that will return
一个随机整数
a random integer
均匀分布在 1 到 1000 的范围内
uniformly distributed in the range from one to 1000
所以我们会有类似的承诺
so we'll have like pledge
例如 4 5 6
4 5 6 for example
所以这
so this
模拟将质押发送到外部服务
simulates sending the pledge to the external service
但是这个功能
but this function
还需要兑现记忆中的质押
also needs to cash the pledge in memory
所以现金只是一个清单
so the cash is just going to be a list
在该列表中，我们想要我们的承诺信息
and inside that list we want our pledge information
我们将把它表示为一个元组
and we're going to represent that as a tuple
元组的第一个元素将是
the first element of the tuple will be the
人名
person's name
然后是第二个
and then the second
要素将是他们承诺多少
element will be how much they pledge
所以拉里承诺10美元
so larry pledge $10
所以如果板条箱承诺被拉里和锡召唤
so if crate pledge gets called with larry and tin
那么我们的现金看起来就像这样
then our cash is going to look exactly like this
好的，那么我们最近的承诺功能应该怎么做
okay so what should our recent pledges function do
好吧，它需要返回
well it needs to return
最近的
the most recent
承诺，这是我们的现金
pledges and that's our cash
所以如果我们的现金目前是这个清单
so if our cash is currently this list
那么它需要返回该列表
then it would need to return that list
所以坚持我们的野生动物主题
so sticking with our wildlife theme
这是房间里的大鳄鱼
here's the big crocodile in the room
我们在哪里存放这些现金
where do we store this cash
以便 crate 质押功能可以更新它
so that the crate pledge function can update it
然后最近的质押功能可以返回
and then the recent pledges function can return
那些承诺
those pledges
井模块不能保持状态
well modules can't hold state
模块不像
modules aren't like
对象华丽语言中的对象
objects in an object ornate language
可以保持状态
that can hold state
在实例变量中
in instance variables
啊，但事实证明进程可以保持状态
ah but it turns out processes can hold state
在质押服务器中
in the pledge server
模块将定义一个名为listen loop的函数
module will define a function named listen loop
不断接收和处理
that continuously receives and handles
无限循环中的消息
messages in an endless loop
并将产生一个运行该功能的进程
and will spawn a process that runs that function
在那个服务器进程中将保持一些内部状态
in that server process will keep some internal state
最近认捐的现金
a cash of recent pledges
当过程开始时
when the process starts
它的初始状态将是一个空的长生不老药列表
its initial state will be an empty elixir list
当我们得到我们的第一个承诺
when we get our first pledge
请求处理过程将发送一条消息
the request handling process will send a message
到服务器进程
to the server process
与质押信息
with the pledge information
当服务器收到该消息时
when the server receives that message
承诺信息
the pledge info
将传递给外部服务
will get passed along to the external service
我们不会关心这是怎么发生的
we won't concern ourselves with how that happens
更相关
more relevant
达到我们的目标
to our objective
服务器进程将
the server process will
还将质押添加到现金中
also add the pledge to the cash
这是服务器进程管理的状态
which is the state managed by the server process
然后服务器进程将发回一条消息
the server process will then send a message back
对请求
to the request
处理过程
handling process
表示质押创建成功
indicating that the pledge was successfully created
或不是请求
or not the request
然后嚎叫过程
howling process then
发回相应的 http 响应
sends a corresponding http response back
给它的客户
to its client
例如浏览器和进程死亡
for example a browser and the process dies
然后当我们得到我们的第二个并且希望
then when we get our 2nd and hopefully
随后的承诺
subsequent pledges
请求嚎叫过程将向此发送消息
the request howling process will send a message to this
相同的服务器进程更新其现有现金
same server process updating its existing cash
然后当要求最近的承诺时
then when the recent pledges are requested
请求处理过程将发送一个
the request handling process will send a
给服务器进程的不同消息
different message to the server process
当服务器收到该消息时
when the server receives that message
它会发回一条消息
it will send a message back
包括现金认捐
that includes the pledges in the cash
所以服务器进程需要接收
so the server process will need to receive
并能够处理不同类型的消息
and be able to handle different kinds of messages
这很有趣
this is pretty interesting
Elixir 进程可以存储状态
elixir processes can store state
和其他过程可以改变
and other processes can change
或通过发送消息检索该状态
or retrieve that state by sending messages
退后一步
stepping back
我们看到两种不同类型的过程
we see two different types of processes
每个都有特定的角色
each with specific roles
服务器进程通常是我们长期运行的进程
a server process is typically our long running process
保持状态
that maintains state
我们稍后会看到
and as we'll see later
也可以同时执行任意工作
can also perform arbitrary work concurrently
另一方面，客户端进程
client processes on the other hand
向服务器发送和接收消息
send to and receive messages from the server